hahaha
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frank de Freitas
and welcome to another broadcast of
holotalk I'd like to welcome the new
iTune listeners who are tuning in for
the first time to the program and also
any other podcast listeners who are
listening through subscription programs
such as
podcasting.net my guest for this show is
Claus Conan who is with polo star in
Hamburg Germany and this is a rather
unusual type of show since it began as a
phone call that I received from Kloss a
few weeks ago and during that phone call
I said to him why don't we do this into
a program he was announcing a holography
exhibit that was going to be starting in
Europe in 2006 running into 2007 and I
thought it would make a great hollow
talk program while you're listening to
this you'll hear me start off on the
telephone and then eventually I move
over to a microphone here in the studio
so I just wanted to explain that little
bit of discrepancy that you will hear
during the recording it's actually a
phone conversation between the two of us
that happened to be recorded with
Colossus permission of course for the
whole talk broadcast that you're about
to listen to so without further Ado
let's move on to this Edition of
holotalk and I look forward to having
you back once again for continuing shows
throughout the rest of the Year this is
Frankie Freitas and thanks for listening
right now as of now I'm recording why
don't you uh
tell me a little bit about what it is
that that's coming up for you
uh several things I started already I I
encourage you about the
um
new technology we have developed here
together with my partner Hannah
okay
for 20 years all right and and work with
all the guys and James River Products
and and
Crown Royal
mostly with embossing yes mostly with
embossing and okay kind of technology so
we're setting up a new very big plant
here of industrial production maybe you
should tell everyone where here is here
is a Hamburg Hamburg in Good Old Germany
good which is Europe
City in the north of Germany yes very
famous for the star Club back in the uh
it's very close to me here I'm in San
Pauli area with my office is it still
located there I imagine it must be a
historic site yeah it is
the road still it's called The Fly hide
where it's been and the Beatles played
and there's big music club right on the
other side now but it's not opened at
Star Club I say anymore but listen let
me continue with this we have developed
some kind of interesting technology uh
mentioned which is the UV technology
which this is known already worldwide
but we have modified it in a very
interesting way which allows us to more
or less print holograms on any kind of
surface
doesn't make any difference whether it's
paper
unrolled or textile or film
that's incredible yeah
but incredible and partial printing on
it and a better quality than ever been
before because yeah it's possible to
measure it of course but this is not
what I wanted to tell you I mean nothing
is maybe just to finish this what we are
doing and what's coming up is also in
our r d project uh which we we got one
together with the company were afraid
antivirus used to okay
the Masters here in 1986 also close
Hamburg at the old and famous Hall of
com okay it still exists and we also are
working with it with machinery and r d
project so we're getting a very
interesting r d project by German
government
in cooperation with University to other
companies and
um
they have several locations all over
Germany and
private Institute but very very
professional in r d project they
developed MP3 standards no kidding yeah
this this is in an event invention of a
throne of exertion yeah so we got a very
interesting r d project in holography
which is explosive
structuring explosive copying Magnetic
Tape was invented in Germany as well
yeah this is through Magnetic Tape yeah
yeah
but this is something I just wanted to
tell you about what's going on and
what's coming up here but actually I
would like to talk with you about a
corporation and regard to something I've
been planning for years and it's
completely ready now developed which is
a europe-wide travel exhibition okay
okay this is a holography exhibition yes
and all 3D Technologies and techniques
available will be shown not only
holography but just it cools through
history of philography yes
from the beginnings of stereograms and
stereoscopy and and lenticulars and 3D
movies up to present Technologies and
future Technologies 3D the data storage
and 3D projection systems and of course
one of the largest travel exhibitions
ever been shown so we are going to show
it in in Hamburg in Berlin in London in
Barcelona Paris Paris Milan
anything else Amsterdam
and what are what are the dates for this
to begin the date is
um
2006 the the main time will be 2007 so
it's
um I see 60 years of logophy
you know Dennis Carver worth and he
published his work in 48 but he worked
47 he worked in and and himself said he
developed and made that ex their tests
in 1947. yes I've always quoted 1947
instead of 48 but I always see 48
printed yeah
but it is it is um it's been published
in 48 yeah his work this is as far as I
I have checked it out so
um and I am preparing a kugatorium we
call it over here do you know what I'm
talking about no I do not the curatorium
a curator curator which is an Arts when
you you know oh yes exactly now yes I do
and this is what we are preparing and
I'm
um
involving one friend of mine who is a
design professor at the Hamburg
University
and he will be one of the creators and
write something in the in the catalog
and we have very interesting collection
available and together already the
German
um it's an optical company and and
glasses a chain shop chain called
Fuelman he's got a huge collection the
Fuelman collection yes of holograms and
I'm also in in contact with the MIT
Museum collection okay and would like to
involve and invite you as well well
thank you
and what capacity may I be able to help
you
um first of all I would think to
um to just be member of the curatorium
okay we are we are
um having probably eight eight persons
maximum worldwide
and as I mentioned the professor is one
of them another one is a worldwide
active artist and he's an architect who
who just did the the Spanish booth on
the Expo in Japan I see yeah I guess
very nice work he's quite famous it is
too and he will do the design with us
his name is
living in Spain but he saw the German
and
um so and holography artists of course
I'm thinking about taking the other U.S
American I would like to ask Dr John
Perry Oh yes
I think he might be interested in just
being member of the curatorium
we will also look for it for a budget
from our sponsors because there are
sponsors involved of course have to be I
mean this is a very big project yes and
I have sent you the mail yes
so maybe maybe you can check in the
meantime whether you've received it
because you will see what's all written
in there yes it's here is it yes it is I
haven't had a chance to read it because
I'm speaking with you through through a
microphone now with headphones on since
we're doing the show
you can hear it's a little bit different
yeah
more far away do I seem how's this is
this a little bit better for you now
yeah it's better okay
so the the treatment have you opened the
treatment PDF file no I have not I don't
want a chance losing the audio file
that's being recorded on the computer as
as we're speaking okay
but I will go in there and let me let's
you know what I feel like living
dangerously today let me go in here and
open this up
yeah
I have to turn my head away from the
microphone
and of course since my eyes are so bad I
have to put glasses on now because I'm
far away from the screen
what operating system are you using oh
I've always been on Macintosh Apple yes
yeah very good one
see 3D lab Hamburg presents Holo world
the world the world of holograms right
60 years of holography
yes
this is something that I can include on
the website as a download for everyone
we have an agency involved already and I
have already partnered though there is
um
a meeting now do you remember National
Geographics they did a cover in the 80s
oh yeah sure yeah a couple covers yeah
right a couple of them right but I'm
talking about the one with the with the
McDonald's ad on the back side okay yes
that's the one with the exploding globe
on the front yeah yeah the exploring
Globe I love it
okay
so um
excellent they they heard about because
their web designer met me and I told him
about the exhibit and now they are quite
interested in doing something similar
here in Europe the cover and also some
kind of
Articles and information about the
exhibition and everything so
um but this will be decided in
Washington next week okay the the um the
international
um
press
press National Geographic people they
they meet in Washington because that's
the the main office obviously
so is there going to be any
representatives there from
your group
no they just wanted to have this this
written thing which you also can see
here now this treatment yeah because
this this is at the moment in our
agencies working on doing a a official
presentation paper I see that'll be done
in German you know and then afterwards
being translated into English but I mean
you see it's starting in September 2006
in Hamburg yes I see that so
um
you know this is not that far I mean we
work on it with the agency but this was
a short English description I made
myself it's very well written
is it yes of course I was not sure thank
you I really wasn't sure
I was like uh can I give it away like
this because we are still working on
with the agency and doing it very
perfect and and and better and more
yeah
and and what capacity can I be of
service to you
first of all I wanted to invite you to
be part of the curatorium yes and what
responsibilities will that entail
yeah and I mean you have produced
Holograms as well oh sure so
so we could show
your work I also would like to show
us work there okay thank you and and I
mean this is in a way historical like a
thing so and and you can see I mean
there's a big list the Consortium this
won't be lots of work for you maybe
um of course you can I think there
shouldn't be a problem to
it on the website also because it's it's
that far already you know otherwise the
only risk might be that someone else is
trying to do something similar also the
idea is good people will love it and as
you can see on the list of the first
site on the first page you can see I
mean this will be a big area with a lot
of things to see this is in conjunction
with
another tour a larger tour that's just
basically four three-dimensional
Technologies in the history right
holography is a sub subdivision of that
no it's maybe a lot of people it's
mainly holography yeah it's mainly
holography and all the other things are
subdivisions 3D techniques or
lenticulars or stereograms it's
interesting to show them yes and and
give their people glasses and sure I
will also do video projection I did that
12 or more years ago already here in
Hamburg uh with with Autumn 3D company
in the United States
material so with the video projections
that meanwhile such a lot of
um
um new technologies or many new
technologies are available oh absolutely
and and it's unbelievable to show all
that they showed at the Expo a of your
meter which is I don't know 150 inches
uh um uh screen 3D auto stereoscopic
auto stereoscopic screen
without glasses you stand there run
front and it's a depth of 40 50 inches
that's incredible yeah and I mean people
need to see these kind of things um I
think and they like it they love it I
like it so any any chance of bringing it
over to the states
actually we have meanwhile so high level
contacts there to in Barcelona there is
once a year now in June in two weeks
starting it's on the Zona Festival
which is arts and media media arts
International media arts artists
musicians festivals
and it's very high International many
Americans come over there and it looks
like we can even be in Barcelona in in
the same building area at the time of
the
and this if this happens we will
probably get inquiries from New York or
the United States because of the tour I
mean there are Americans involved lots
of holograms are made by Americans
and and but worldwide and Russians and
Europeans so worldwide yes
um so
um I think this might be might be
possible but I
I don't think about the moment
I mean you know there were I think the
Hologram the show will be good enough to
be on World Tour but first of all we do
the Europe tour yes we're living here
yeah of course all the contacts and
everything I think it's I think it's
it's great definitely I mean I can I
have I have an idea already of course
and I know all all the different things
you know you probably also will
understand when you read it yeah what
what I'm talking about oh absolutely
sure so we have a pulse laser system
recording system
now what have you been doing with the
pulse laser system over there is there a
is there a market for post portraits of
people or not that not much yeah hour is
is ours is not set up at the moment
because we are we're preparing this big
production plan but new technologies
in here right now this year we are
starting to build it up and and we have
lots of equipment which is not
completely set up at the moment but
there is another friend of mine who's
who got the other uh in Germany the
other parts laser system in south of
Germany Hall of wood is the company
and Tim
and he's got one and I made
with our system I made in with antasia
86 we made Nina hog and hologram Ina
Hagen you know her no I do not she's a
rock singer and she's often in the
United States she was in New York so
recently normally living in L.A maybe my
daughters know her I'll have to ask yeah
no problem
I'm an old man yeah so I mean we all are
a little but I'm not old I'm not that
old actually I I don't know I even look
very young people never believe me my
age you sound Young
I'm I'm nearly 40 46 oh yeah in two
weeks I'll be 46. you have a very good
sound to your voice for 40 seconds
usually sometimes you can even tell the
General Health and vitality of people
through their voice yeah I don't think
so yeah
but this always depends on my mood
I can't tell you I can give you a link
if you want to see
if you're online yeah I'm online where
am I going to go then see how I really
look but it's a little freaky picture
page that's all right give me the
address
um go to
Holo star
.com star
um dot d e dot d e
slash yeah
uh photos this is the German photos
which is okay as in in fantasy oh okay
f-o-t-o-s
okay dot HTML HTML
thank you
should I see can I see your baby picture
there yes that's me oh there you are
look at this
big claws playing the guitar yes that
was when I was 20 years old
oh you're a good looking guy
oh I don't know oh there's Nina huh yeah
this is Nina the crazy Nina down there
yeah yeah she's got uh
fishnet stockings on
fishnet oh yes yes
crazy I tell you it's got a nice
daughters
oh look at you boy you're having a good
time here with some of these shots
this was in the shop you see the one
with with his
they're very colorful
photo oh yeah are these all recent
pictures of you no this no a recent
picture is done there that was in the
studio blah blah blah recent is look at
the last two ones okay yeah which one
you're online with my heart
the guy on the left yeah right hand and
and with their hearts yes this is how I
nowadays look wow and you're 46 huh yes
I am wow
I don't know
that's amazing
yeah you you live uh you live a good
life
I I hope to good diet food no good food
yeah logical Foods yeah good good
healthy foods right yes yeah that's
important huh
yeah it's not something wow you could in
that last picture you could pass for
like in in your 20s like a college
student yeah yeah I always look like a
like a baby face
maybe this is someone told me maybe and
and he also he knows one in Berlin the
guy he is looking like 37 years old yeah
but he was born in 1937.
and he's got his son who is end of 50s
with a beard and everything
but his father looks like a son
he said maybe it's a
genetic defect something
wow you know gray hair or anything huh
no gray hair yeah I just started turning
white a couple years ago and man it's
really coming on now
yeah yeah come forward I'm 49 I'll be 50
soon yeah yeah so this is we're going on
to 50. this is yeah
the first pictures are so funny with the
little child you know me with 50 months
old yeah with a screwdriver and and a
plaque and and so this is
yeah your second picture there you look
a little bit like an American actor we
have over here's Kevin Bacon
Kevin Bacon yeah in that second picture
there and a young Kevin Bacon huh
yeah laser Master at Labor whole press
Holo press Hollow common and Holo press
we were in Lubeck for a couple of years
yeah some nice equipment in the
background there yeah yeah
and everything
wow you're yeah great
okay go so how's your your partner is uh
doing okay you could
you could just show you something else
go to Hulu
go right to the initial page the front
page yeah okay you can also have it on
the English home page but it doesn't
matter okay
but you're on the German one now yeah
that's fine yeah
um be interested
yeah here
go on in the left upper frame all right
there's the third position
yes how is Oliver made yeah click that
mm-hmm
and then click Massachusetts okay I see
it yeah I'm going there now okay great
oh there's there's Fred huh there's Fred
here we are the Frets and and and then
and the other one this is my
1986. that was in 1986 right I was just
getting started with my own lab in 83.
ah so uh
here there was a big equipment nice
equipment but it's all been stolen by
German industry
we could ride really because make a
movie about this what all happened
but very good that I finally reached you
yeah you must you must have an
interesting calling plan that you can
stay on the phone so long from Germany
what do you have a calling plan or
something I just got a calling plan it
is fine it is this is a Honda net which
is not the official German Telecom they
are quite expensive I mean they really
cost us ten thousands because we often
in the past and 80s already at that time
it really was
make phone calls yeah United States
through Telecom like I don't know six
bucks a minute or something oh God
unbelievable
but um no no this is much cheaper now
and these are
long distance I don't know fiberglass
line or saddle I think this is a
fiberglass line yeah the connection's
real it's a wonderful connection just
around the corner yeah yeah there's this
digital okay if you if you could say
anything to the folks who would be
listening you've heard these shows
before on the web right yeah these whole
talk shows yeah yeah if you could say
anything to any of the listeners what
would you say
oh what would you tell them they're
listening to you right now
oh they're they're not listening to you
live I mean I'm going to edit this and
put it up but they'll they'll be
listening to what we're talking stay
tuned to hold a talk and keep interested
in allography it's still future and
fantasy and as written in my in my
concept about the Holo show you probably
just have opened on top there I would
say holography is a true intersection of
art Science and Technology
Professor Stephen Benton said
once once yes I'm sure several times I'm
sure yeah probably
more times than you wanted to yeah I
will go into details and send you send
you a mail I hope it comes through this
time directly email or regular mail yeah
no email email okay
yeah that's the oddest thing I'm you
know I should still have deleted email
from uh because there are some emails
that make it through that are spam it
doesn't get every one of them I'm going
to go back in there and see if somehow I
uh I accidentally deleted that
and I do because I always I always I
always send email back and forth between
people you know I would never
intentionally uh not send an email to
someone and just let it sit I mean
sometimes I let the emails pile up for a
few days and then maybe on a Wednesday
night or a Saturday night I'll sit down
and answer all of them from the past few
days you know
that all right yeah send send me if you
send you more information okay yeah so
I'll put that on yeah and people can
download that at the website you're
right right no I'll send I'll make it
right now and send it in about five or
ten minutes okay
uh yeah so it's been good talking to you
good talking to you and now you're a
guest on whole talk so look for my
announcements when you're going to be on
there
I will all right
thank you thanks a lot right have a nice
afternoon you too bye bye
foreign